# Eric Noll

(317) 847-4595 · eric.noll@northwestern.edu

#### **Summary**

Energetic and dedicated human resources professional with over five years of experience in talent acquisition and human resources in a multitude of environments, including corporate and higher education. SHRM certified with a passion for employee relations and organizational development through implementation of recommended best practices and policies.

# **Education**

Ball State University: Bachelor's2013Major: Music EducationMuncie, IN

**SHRM-CP** 

Certified: March 2019

### **Work History**

#### Northwestern University - Office of Human Resources

Talent Acquisition Partner

Chicago, IL August 2017 – Present

- Accountable for delivering full-cycle recruitment services to University client groups, including
  developing and implementing strong recruiting strategies, source active and passive candidates to
  minimum and preferred qualifications, provide guidance on interviewing and hiring best practices,
  and prepare & negotiate offers for non-exempt and exempt roles.
- Develop and maintain strong business partnerships, with hiring managers and department leaders, through strategic collaboration on complex human resources solutions, hiring best practices, candidate selection, and offer equity.
- Work with Northwestern employees on effective resume writing, interviewing best practices, and application process guidance while maintaining alignment with Northwestern's policies.
- Well-versed in using Northwestern University's MyHR and Peoplesoft systems for creating, posting, and managing various job openings in eRecruit.
- Create a standard operating procedure and process maps for offer approvals, extensions, and rescissions and worked to edit existing and create new content for the HR website redesign.
- Implement the new Northwestern Talent Acquisition branding strategy, created and managed the usage of the new Twitter account, trained the team on social media best practices and effective utilization of the new photoshop tool.

GEICO Chevy Chase, MD
Technical Recruiter May 2016 - March 2017

- Full-cycle recruiter working directly with GEICO's hiring managers and directors to understand their business needs, develop recruiting strategies, and attract top IT talent, exceeding the department's quarterly hiring goals.
- Facilitated and lead various portions of the monthly new hire training, GEICO 101, utilizing visual aids and answering various questions.

- Lead the improvement and re-implementation of GEICO's new Referral Program through creation of new monthly campaign ads and events leading to an increase of referrals in the GEICO corporate and satellite offices.
- Utilized GEICO's applicant tracking system (ATS), Taleo, to track all recruiting data, documenting everything including prescreening and interview assessments and new hire information.
- Attracted quality talent using sourcing techniques with LinkedIn Recruiter, candidate pipelining, and various job boards alongside various GEICO sponsored recruiter events such as careers fairs and technology meetups.

ModisLaurel, MDTechnical RecruiterDec 2014 - May 2016

- Full-cycle, agency recruiter that worked with external business partners and hiring managers to develop strong business partnerships, recruiting strategies, and attract top IT talent.
- Responsible for training and developing new employees on proper sales and recruitment strategies, sourcing and pipelining, and organization and development.
- Utilized the applicant tracking system to track all recruiting data, documenting everything through the candidate process
- Utilized various sourcing methods with cold calling, Modis ATS, skillset pipelining, LinkedIn Recruiter, and various job boards.

Defender DirectIndianapolis, INHuman Resources AssistantApril 2014 – Oct 2014

- Assisted with the Human Resources department, finance department, regional directors, and various other departments
- Used PeopleSoft to update new and current employee information and file and approve various Human Resources paperwork for ADT technicians including: leave requests and benefits processing.

**Enterprise Rent-a-car** *Management Assistant* 

Indianapolis, IN June 2013 – Mar 2014

## **Technical Skills**

PeopleSoft, Kronos, Adobe Photoshop Adobe Acrobat, Microsoft Office Suite, TimeTrade, Box, Taleo (Oracle), ADP, E-Verify, LinkedIn Recruiter, Google Docs